tactics.com 2008-12-17

# Security & Privacy

Tactics uses 128-bit Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) encryption technology to prevent third parties from reading the information you enter during our online Checkout process. We have chosen Verisign® as our SSL digital certificate provider to offer you the most secure certificate services available. 

To ensure your online transaction is secure during the Checkout process, make sure the gold key icon appears connected in the lower left corner for Netscape 3.0 browsers or that the padlock icon appears in the lower right corner for all Internet Explorer or Netscape 4.0+ browsers. 

Keep in mind that not all browsers, and some firewalls (often used in office settings), allow transmittal of information through SSL technology. If you are experiencing difficulties submitting your order through our online Checkout process, please do not hesitate to call us toll-free in the U.S. at 1.888.450.5060 or 1.541.349.0087 (International) to place your order. 

Please keep in mind that for your protection we do not store credit card numbers in our database. Once the transaction is complete, we have no way of accessing your credit card number. Additionally, if you are shipping an order to an address other than your billing address, your order may be delayed for verification. 

We respect the privacy of our customers and do not sell your personal information to anyone. This privacy statement discloses our information-gathering and dissemination practices. If you have any questions or concerns, we invite you to contact us directly for more information regarding our commitment to your privacy. 

**What Information We Collect and Why:**

We may use our customers’ Internet Protocol (IP) addresses to help diagnose problems with our own technology and to administer the Tactics website. The IP addresses we collect do not link to or reveal any personally identifiable information of our customers. In addition, like virtually all e-commerce sites, we use cookies to keep track of any products in your shopping cart to ensure a successful online ordering process. 

Tactics also uses aggregate demographic and site-traffic data internally, and we may provide this aggregate information about our customers, sales, traffic patterns, and related site information to trusted third-parties, but this information does not disclose our users’ personally identifiable information. 

Our online Checkout process asks you to give us certain contact information (like your name, address, and email address). We use this information to speed up the order process and to contact you when you request or when it’s absolutely necessary (for example, if there’s a problem fulfilling your order). When you choose to order from us, we must also collect billing and shipping information, including credit card numbers. This information is required to charge you for your purchases, to process and ship your order, and to contact you if there’s any problem with your order. In order to process payment information and fulfill our customers’ orders, some billing and shipping information is provided to trusted third-parties such as credit card processing institutions and carriers like UPS. They do not use this information for secondary purposes, however. 

Tactics may occasionally use registration or order information to contact you about our promotions, special events, or to send you a catalog. In addition, at times Tactics may send offers to you on behalf of other selected businesses. However, we do not give those businesses your personal information. If you are not interested in receiving communications about Tactics, or offers made on behalf of other businesses, you may opt-out of receiving such future communications (see below). 

**Opting Out:**

If you are no longer interested in receiving communications from Tactics, you have several options for terminating any future contact. To stop receiving communications from us, you can use any of the following methods (please specify whether you would like to stop receiving communications about Tactics, offers made on behalf of other businesses, or both): 

> > **1\. You can email us at:**  
> 
>>
> 
>> 
>> **2\. You can mail us at:**  
> 
>>
>>> Tactics  
>  Attn: Opting Out  
>  P.O. Box 1473  
>  Eugene, OR 97440  
> 
>> 
>> **3\. You can call us:**  
> 
>>
>>> 1.888.450.5060 (U.S. toll-free)  
>  1.541.349.0087 (International)  
> 
>> 
>> **4\. You can fax us at:**  
> 
>>
>>> 1.541.349.2007  
>
